Patrick McGuigan

Software Engineer

339.788.1008 // Denver, Colorado

Patrick.McGuigan5@gmail.com // https://www.linkedin.com/in/patrickmcguigan // https://pmsoftware.netlify.app // https://github.com/pattshreds //

I am a Software Engineer with experience building projects using **Ruby on Rails**, **Javascript**, **ReactJS**, **Redux**, **PostgreSQL**, **MongoDB**, **Docker and NodeJS** as well as other programming languages and technologies. My focus includes putting organization, smooth functionality and responsive design at the heart of what I provide. With backgrounds in instruction, sales and graphic design, I have learned to prioritize dynamic problem solving and strong communication. While my passion is in technology, development, and design I also feel a great sense of satisfaction when learning something new.

SKILLS

Languages, Frameworks & Libraries //

JavaScript, React, React-Spring, Python, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, NodeJS, ExpressJS, AJAX, Redux, HTML, CSS.

Management & Deployment //

Docker, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Command Line.

Databases //

PostgreSQL, RDBMS, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose

Methodologies //

Object-Oriented Programming, MVC Pattern, Test-Driven Development, Responsive Design, Authentication, User Stories, ERDs, Wireframing, Agile Development, Scrum.

Proficiencies //

Database Architecture, Optimization, Data Structures, Version Repository, Web API, Full-Stack Web Development.

PROJECTS

PokéSearch // GitHub

PokéSearch is a frontend application built in **HTML**, **CSS**, **Javascript**, and **jQuery** using a third party API. This application allows the user to search the Pokédex-style database to learn information about each Pokémon, and various other items found in the games. This project shows my ability to optimize until everything (or nearly everything) works and is built in an efficient way.

Moodset // GitHub

Moodset is a full stack application built with Javascript, NodeJS, Mongoose, ExpressJS, and .EJS using an MVC design pattern. This application allows users to create, view, edit, and delete playlists using their own uploaded mp3 files. One of the main challenges I encountered was getting MP3 files to upload and play. My skills in problem solving allowed me to research and build until I was able to solve this problem.

Infinite Savannah // GitHub

Infinite Savannah is a full stack application built with a **MERN stack** (MongoDB, ExpressJS, React, NodeJS). The application allows the user to explore a retro-futuristic skateshop, and create, view, edit, and delete items via a user-friendly interface. Infinite Savannah was a team effort which relied on **Agile** and **Trello** to manage progress.

Rezu // GitHub

Rezu is a full stack application built with a **PERN stack** (PostgreSQL, ExpressJS, React, NodeJS). This full stack application utilizes React to create a responsive and easy-to-use product review

website that I built as a passion project to learn how to integrate React with a PostgreSQL database. Developed this application to learn how to integrate React with a PostgreSQL database. I displayed strategic planning by figuring out how I was going to create and organize this database before starting the project.

EXPERIENCE

Production Specialist // Friction Labs // 2021 -

- Work with the production team to take the Friction Labs product from raw materials to clean, sealed and ready-to-ship.
- Use my production expertise to modify and improve our production workflow by designing new methods for each step in the process when necessary, finding more efficient tools, and brainstorming how to maximize production efforts without working harder.
- Maintain and repair production machinery to ensure efficiency and a high quality product.

Software Engineer // Hack for LA // 2022 - 2023

• Worked with the HFLA website team using Git to fix front-end & back-end issues via pull requests. Attended weekly meetings to discuss current and potential future issues on the HFLA website.

Sales Advisor // PMG - Porsche // 2018 - 2020

- Developed long lasting relationships with clients through strong and consistent communication.
- Worked as a team with all departments to ensure a smooth all around process.
- Executed professional sales streams that lead to efficiency and organization by utilizing a good CRM and staying up to date with it.
- Worked to ensure a pleasant sales atmosphere and experience for all of my clients by offering snacks or beverages, and making sure I never left them waiting too long without physically making sure they were comfortable.

Supervisor, Route Setter, Instructor // Rock Spot Climbing // 2012 - 2018

- Oversaw all gym operations and delegated tasks to employees.
- Prepared team practice itineraries for our B-level climbing team.
- Designed intuitive, and fun climbing routes of all levels, and implemented them onto the climbing surface using proper tools and safety.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive Certificate // General Assembly // Remote **B.A. in Graphic Design** // Curry College // Boston, Massachusetts